# Pablo Lopez Alonso

al.pablo20@gmail.com • https://www.linkedin.com/in/pablo-lopez-alonso/

## **Career Profile**

Computational Linguist looking to build effective language technology solutions. Four years of experience in linguistics, text annotation, and data analysis. Proven experience working in Agile for developing a Finance voice virtual assistant (VUI), CX conversational and flow design, and POC development.

#### **Experience**

AT&T International

Mexico City, Mexico

Sr. Tech Specialist Computational Linguistics/CX

November 2020-Present

- Designed and presented conversational flows for a virtual assistant to save 60-80k minutes/month of human conversation
- Wrote and updated the documentation of our financial virtual assistant by keeping constant communication with development team, architect, and internal clients
- Worked along AI architect and developers on POCs to transition from an IVR contact center to a virtual assistant
- Provided CX conversational improvements for our finance virtual assistant by analyzing large-scale data sets to keep a call contention rate of ~70%

### Stony Brook University, Computational Linguistics Program

Stony Brook, NY

NLP Analysis of LGBT Terms on Twitter

Fall 2019

Analyzed a sample of 1 million tweets containing LGBTQ terms in relation to historical events

Italian Particle Verb Tree Automaton

Spring 2019

• Successfully developed a python script that processes up to 90% of Italian Particle Verbs

**Stony Brook University** 

Stony Brook, NY

Teaching Assistant

September 2018-May 2020

- Monitored the academic progress of 200 college students in 2 years
- Planned and led classes for 60 undergraduate students every week

**Luther College** 

Decorah, IA

Native Language Revitalization Project, Linguistics Program

Summer 2016

• Collected, transcribed, and analyzed linguistic data for a conference presentation and proceedings paper

Academic Assistant, Linguistics, Spanish, German, and Italian Departments

October 2013-May 2017

- Assessed the assignments and progress of 250 college students in 2 years
- Translated 130 pages of a from Italian to Spanish and from German to English
- Assisted with transcription and bibliography of 2 doctoral dissertations

#### Education

**DeepLearning.AI,** TensorFlow Developer Professional Certificate

September 2020

Stony Brook University, Stony Brook, NY, USA, MA in Computational Linguistics,

August 2020

**Luther College,** Decorah, IA, USA, *BA cum laude,* German, Minor: Linguistics *Münster Program Study Abroad*, Münster, Germany

May 2017 February–May 2016

### Languages and Skills

Natural – Spanish (native), English (near-native), German (upper-intermediate), Italian (upper-intermediate)
Programming – Python (TensorFlow, NLTK, Regular Expressions, MatPlot Lib), Git/Github, Command Line
Skills – AWS (Lex, Connect, S3, DynamoDB, Polly), MS Suite (Word, Excel), Flow design (Visio)